<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Toomas Vendelin on vendelin.org</title>
    <link>https://vendelin.org/authors/tvendelin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Toomas Vendelin on vendelin.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 06:32:37 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vendelin.org/authors/tvendelin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Git: A Dialogue Between a Language Teacher and a Linux Sysadmin</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/git-language-learn/dialogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 16:24:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/git-language-learn/dialogue/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;What is Git?&amp;rsquo;, Yuni asks. Yuni is an online teacher of Indonesian and an aspiring Linux user.
&amp;lsquo;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s sort of a cross between a time machine and a kitchen blender, the one you make your smoothies with from all these exotic fruits that grow in your backyard&amp;rsquo;, Toomas responds. Toomas is a programmer and a Linux sysadmin.
&amp;lsquo;I know my kitchen blender A to Z&amp;rsquo;, says Yuni proudly. &amp;lsquo;Why don&amp;rsquo;t you tell me about time machine part first?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual Blogging with Hugo - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/introduction-multilngual-blogging-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 19:53:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/introduction-multilngual-blogging-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is a tool for building a multilingual static site. Combined with hosting on GitHub, your site will run on zero-budget, and without the hurdles of maintaining any web- or database servers. You will also enjoy the full control over your code.
Hugo allows you to separate writing content (you travel stories, cooking recipes, etc.) from designing your web site. You will need to design a bunch of HTML templates, write your stories, and Hugo will make the two a happy marriage with just a single four-letter word you type in a terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging tips for foreign language students</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/blog-learning-foreign-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 16:24:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/blog-learning-foreign-language/</guid>
      <description>Do you brag about learning a foreign language? Blog about it instead! Open-source tools, zero budget, no imposed advertisement. The outcome: better organized learning records, plus a few useful skills acquired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you brag about learning a foreign language? Blog about it instead!</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/blog-learning-foreign-language/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 16:24:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/blog-learning-foreign-language/overview/</guid>
      <description>So, do you brag about learning a foreign language? Let&amp;rsquo;s admit: most of us do, in one form or another. Don&amp;rsquo;t you update your social media profiles, your CV, or suddenly greet a colleague in a coffee kitchen in his native tongue, which you incidently happen to learn? Learning a foreign language requires an effort. Diminished capability to express yourself can also be frustrating at times. And so we seek additional motivation and approval from people around us, and so we brag, in one form or another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Hugo</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/install-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 18:38:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/install-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo comes in a single binary file. Download the archive from releases page to your ~/Downloads directory. The version and checksums in the examples will likely be different, of course.
Calculate the checksum:
openssl sha256 -hex -r ~/Downloads/hugo_0.69.2_macOS-64bit.tar.gz f58e9312ee292c082c5833a128e751c1d07c5fb0da1b7584c09131f18e2ccf52 */Users/you/Downloads/hugo_0.69.2_macOS-64bit.tar.gz Verify that the checksum matches the one listed in hugo_0.69.2_checksums.txt file, that can be found on the same releases page. Extract the archive you&amp;rsquo;ve just verified:
tar zxvf ~/Downloads/hugo_0.69.2_macOS-64bit.tar.gz Copy the hugo executable to a directory in your $PATH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Up Hugo with Errorist Theme</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/blog-learning-foreign-language/hugo-errorist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 06:48:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/blog-learning-foreign-language/hugo-errorist/</guid>
      <description>windows mac linux   Windows 10 Enable Windows Subsystem Linux (WSL) as described on this Microsoft page . Hugo itself will run on Windows natively, but wdiff won&amp;rsquo;t.
Launch Microsoft Store, search for &amp;lsquo;Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;, and install the latest LTS version (LTS stands for &amp;lsquo;Long term support&amp;rsquo;). As of this writing, this should be Ubuntu 20.04 LTS. Any general-use Linux distribution would do, but I&amp;rsquo;ve picked Ubuntu because for new users it would be easier to find support online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub for Foreign Language Teachers</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/git-language-learn/grammar-exercise-repository-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 16:24:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/git-language-learn/grammar-exercise-repository-github/</guid>
      <description>A Git / GitHub workflow for foreign language students and teachers was briefly discussed in a Skype conversation between Yuni, an online teacher of Indonesian, and Toomas, a Linux system engineer. They have agreed to go though it step by step, and so they did. Here, we are discussing things from the teacher&amp;rsquo;s perspective.
Grammar exercises as a Git repository published on GitHub Yuni creates a new folder on her computer, and initializes a Git repository inside it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaffolding of a Hugo website</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/scaffoldings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:29:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/scaffoldings/</guid>
      <description>Choose a name for your project. It&amp;rsquo;s just a name of a directory and has no other significance. I have chosen &amp;lsquo;multilingua&amp;rsquo; for a name.
In your terminal emulator, run
hugo new site multilingua This will create multilingua directory and produce the output:
Congratulations! Your new Hugo site is created in /Users/tom/learn/hugo/multilingua. Just a few more steps and you&amp;#39;re ready to go: 1. Download a theme into the same-named folder. Choose a theme from https://themes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub for Foreign Language Students</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/git-language-learn/fork-and-complete-grammar-exercise-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 16:24:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/git-language-learn/fork-and-complete-grammar-exercise-github/</guid>
      <description>Grammar exercises published as a Git repository on GitHub can be forked by a student and completed on GitHub directly. Yuni, an online teacher of Indonesian, has created such a repository (see the previous chapter ). It contained just a single exercise. Now, after trying things out, she creates a repository with a set of exercises:
https://github.com/kartikayuni/Exercise-absolute-beginner
Maria, a Yuni&amp;rsquo;s student, got a link to that repository from her teacher, and is about to do her first homework on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Configuration for Multilingual Hugo-Managed Site</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/custom-multilingual-configuration-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 07:34:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/custom-multilingual-configuration-hugo/</guid>
      <description>A multilingual site managed with Hugo static generator requires a couple of extra steps. I essence, you just need to tell Hugo which languages are you going to use, and how these languages are called in these languages (Eesti keel for Estonian, Bahasa Indonesia for Indonesian, etc.). The rest is really optional.
Before we begin, though, I&amp;rsquo;d like to suggest a few
Configuration Adjustments I Choose YAML and config Directory Your project configuration sits by default in config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Theme Tutorial – Very Brief</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/creating-a-theme-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 18:11:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/creating-a-theme-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>A &amp;lsquo;theme&amp;rsquo; in Hugo is a collection of HTML templates, stylesheets and other components that define what your site looks like, and are completely independent of your site content. That is, the very same theme can be used in many different websites. In software lingo this is known as the &amp;lsquo;separation of concerns&amp;rsquo; principle, which reminds of an old Swedish joke claiming that policemen always patrol in pairs because one can read and another can write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Your First Page With Hugo</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/adding-content-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 15:20:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/adding-content-hugo/</guid>
      <description>We are finally ready to start adding content to our Hugo managed website. In your terminal, run:
hugo new poetry/lewis-carroll/the-walrus-and-the-carpenter/index.md Hugo will create the following directory structure under kontent:
kontent/ └── poetry └── lewis-carroll └── the-walrus-and-the-carpenter └── index.md Next, let&amp;rsquo;s open the kontent/poetry/lewis-carroll/the-walrus-and-the-carpenter/index.md. The section between the triple dashes is called &amp;lsquo;front matter&amp;rsquo; on planet Hugo. On my planet we might have called it &amp;lsquo;metadata&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;page parameters&amp;rsquo;. Whatever it&amp;rsquo;s called, it contains variables specific to your page in YAML format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual Content With Hugo</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/create-multilingual-content-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 15:20:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/create-multilingual-content-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Handling Multilingual Content is where Hugo really shines. However, since internationalization (i18n for short) is a pretty complex task, let&amp;rsquo;s throw together a brief list of
Requirements  The content translations should be added in an orderly manner. The content translations should be directly linkable to each other. Templates should not contain any hard-coded language-specific text. Instead, translations for such text should be defined separately and loaded according to the language of the content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Including Images in Multilingual Pages with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/images-multilingual-pages-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 19:15:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/images-multilingual-pages-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Including images in multilingual context is a tricky business. The problem is, an image is a piece of content in its own right, with its own attributes, most important being the caption, which for N languages translates into N captions. In a typical editorial workflow, photos and articles come from two different types of sources (photographers and writers, respectively), and it is a photographer, who writes the captions – in one language at least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Featured Content, Page Summary, Link Texts with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/summary-linktitle-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 19:23:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/summary-linktitle-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Promoting certain articles on the front page of your Hugo managed site will be the next step after creating some content. You will need a summary for each such page, and a text that will appear in links – a link title.
Page Title and Link Title Yes, a page can have more than one title. There are linkTitle and title front matter parameters, and there are corresponding {{.LinkTitle}} and {{.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize Web Page Layout: Hugo Content Types</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/layout-customize-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 07:36:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/layout-customize-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Style consistency is important, and one of the benefits of generating pages with Hugo (as opposed to editing HTML code for each page directly) is a very little amount of HTML code to handle. So far, all the HTML we used were just four (!) template files plus a partial for the breadcrumbs and an image markdown hook. However, some types of content inevitably won&amp;rsquo;t fit the Procrustean bed of a simplistic theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ijen volcano: smoke on the water</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 19:18:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description>Smoke on the water: the crater lake of Ijen volcano in East Java, Indonesia. Gas sulphur, when getting air and moisture, oxidizes and then becomes a cloud of sulphur acid. The crater lake is highly acidic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal and External Links with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/cross-reference-external-links-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 09:11:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/cross-reference-external-links-hugo/</guid>
      <description>The Markdown syntax for creating a link is straightforward, but you likely need to make sure that you are not creating any dead links at least internally to your site. You might also want to customize how different links behave. For instance, you may want the external links to open in a new tab, so that you site visitor stays at your site.
Internal Links Referencing pages of the same site is done with two shortcodes, ref and relref.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spell Check, Build Your Site with Hugo, Publish to GitHub</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/spell-check-build-publish-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 12:56:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/spell-check-build-publish-hugo/</guid>
      <description>So, you are happy with the preview provided by the local Hugo server, and you want to publish your site. Make sure git status doesn&amp;rsquo;t show anything uncommitted changes (you do keep versions of your project under control, don&amp;rsquo;t you?). Then, manually or with some shell magic, change the draft front matter parameter to false for the pages you plan to publish. Restart your Hugo server without the -D option and check that nothing is missing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Togutil of Halmahera – North Maluku, Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/travel/indonesia/north-maluku/togutil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 17:17:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/travel/indonesia/north-maluku/togutil/</guid>
      <description>The Togutil people live in Central and North-Eastern Halmahera Island, the largest in North Maluku, Indonesia. They still move around in jungle barefoot hunting wild boars, caring little about the &amp;lsquo;civilized&amp;rsquo; world around them. Some still wear just a loincloth, although T-shirts and other blessings of industrial production are becoming common. The Togutil live a semi-nomadic life: they have their small settlements, typically in a well-chosen place by a river, but if you decide to pay a surprise visit, be aware there could be nobody home for weeks in a row.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesian Pronouns, or Who Exactly Do You Mean by &#39;Us&#39;?</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/blog-learning-foreign-language/indonesian-pronouns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 19:44:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/blog-learning-foreign-language/indonesian-pronouns/</guid>
      <description>There are two pronouns for the first person plural: kita (inclusive), and kami (exclusive). Tina isn&amp;rsquo;t going to Jakarta with Peter and Dita (Tina is not included = use kami), neither is she returning with them (Tina is not included = use kami). But, once Peter and Dita are back, they go all together to a restaurant. In this case, Tina is included, so use kita.
task my solution solution corrections   Fill the gaps with appropriate pronouns in the following dialogue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git for foreign language students and teachers</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/git-language-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 19:54:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/git-language-learn/</guid>
      <description>Git is a powerful tool for maintaining versions of text files in a project. However, it is often overlooked by the very people who first come to mind when talking of processing texts: translators, editors, foreign language students and teachers.
Git has got a reputation of being a tool only a computer geek can understand and make use of. Not everyone agree, though. Yuni, an online teacher of Indonesian language, and Toomas, a programmer, explore the possibilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Cookbook for a Multilingual Site</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 17:52:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is a tool for building a multilingual static site. Combined with hosting on GitHub, your site will run on zero-budget, and without the hurdles of maintaining any web- or database servers. You will also enjoy the full control over your code. Style consistency is easily manageable across hundreds of pages with only four HTML templates minimally required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Trip to Spain That Ended up in Senegal</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/travel/motorcycle-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 08:04:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/travel/motorcycle-africa/</guid>
      <description>Most reckless deeds start with a deceptively innocent plan.
Evan McGregor thought of going for a motorcycle ride in Spain, and ended up in Eastern Siberia and then North America, the long way round. I thought of going for a motorcycle ride in Spain, and ended up in Dakar, and then Mbur in Senegal.
I moved to Karlsruhe in 2012 by invitation to work for 1&amp;amp;1 Internet AG. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve adopted to the new center of my personal universe, I&amp;rsquo;ve started to look at my new travel options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/geeky/blog-learning-foreign-language/summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/geeky/blog-learning-foreign-language/summary/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s confess: most of us do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description>In West Sahara, somewhere South of Tan-Tan.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>