<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indonesia on vendelin.org</title>
    <link>https://vendelin.org/tags/indonesia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indonesia on vendelin.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 20:10:12 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vendelin.org/tags/indonesia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ijen Volcano in East Java, Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/travel/indonesia/java/ijen-volcano/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 20:10:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/travel/indonesia/java/ijen-volcano/</guid>
      <description>Ijen volcano in the Eastern edge of Java is, in my opinion, the most spectacular and accessible option around to visit a volcanic crater. It is also far less crowded than the Bromo national park, the closest similar site to compare.
Ijen is part of a volcanic complex, and is located in a caldera of the same name. The diameter of the caldera is about 20 km. This is all that remains of the &amp;lsquo;Old Ijen&amp;rsquo; volcano that was once well over 3000 meters tall, until the series of explosive eruptions destroyed it around 50 000 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Togutil of Halmahera – North Maluku, Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://vendelin.org/travel/indonesia/north-maluku/togutil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 17:17:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vendelin.org/travel/indonesia/north-maluku/togutil/</guid>
      <description>The Togutil people live in Central and North-Eastern Halmahera Island, the largest in North Maluku, Indonesia. They still move around in jungle barefoot hunting wild boars, caring little about the &amp;lsquo;civilized&amp;rsquo; world around them. Some still wear just a loincloth, although T-shirts and other blessings of industrial production are becoming common. The Togutil live a semi-nomadic life: they have their small settlements, typically in a well-chosen place by a river, but if you decide to pay a surprise visit, be aware there could be nobody home for weeks in a row.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>